<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://markpmorin.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mark&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://markpmorin.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Working with Statistics Canada Census Data in R</title>
      <link>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-11-07-working-with-statistics-canada-census-data-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-11-07-working-with-statistics-canada-census-data-in-r/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) library(jsonlite) library(sf) In my quest to become familiar with the various data sources that might be useful in understanding my world, next up is Statistics Canaada census data. I should probably just use Cancensus but I like to figure out how these things work, and what value the packages bring to the table before deciding to take a dependency on them.
There are a couple of guides to their web services available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calgary Community Population Change</title>
      <link>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-10-30-calgary-community-population-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-10-30-calgary-community-population-change/</guid>
      <description>In past posts I’ve shown how to pull data from Statistics Canada, and Alberta’s open data site - today I’m going to turn to my local government’s open data site https://data.calgary.ca/. At the same time I’m going to try and map that data. I’ve never produced a map before and I have no experience with GIS systems so I’m going to try and find something really simple to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alberta Royalty Revenue</title>
      <link>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-10-27-alberta-royalty-revenue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-10-27-alberta-royalty-revenue/</guid>
      <description>My previous post left me wondering just how crazy the oil and gas business was in Alberta during those years where median diverged from the rest of Canada. My own recollection is that after oil prices collapsed in the early 1980s, that gas made the biggest contribution to Alberta oil and gas business until the late 2000s when gas prices collapsed due to shale gas coming online, while at the same time all those enormous oilsands projects started coming online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alberta Median Income Using Cansim and Tidyverse</title>
      <link>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-10-26-alberta-median-income-using-cansim-and-tidyverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-10-26-alberta-median-income-using-cansim-and-tidyverse/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post I looked reproducing the chart from the CBC article “Albertans still make the most money, but other provinces are catching up” using base R functionality. In this post I’ll try and do the same using the cansim package to retrieve StatCan data, and the Tidyverse tools to wrangle the data and create the chart.
library(cansim) library(tidyverse) Although the cansim package has the ability to cache data in a SQLLite database, for now I’ll continue to manually manage this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alberta Median Income Using R</title>
      <link>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-10-25-alberta-median-income-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://markpmorin.github.io/post/2021-10-25-alberta-median-income-using-r/</guid>
      <description>I ran across this article on the CBC website “Albertans still make the most money, but other provinces are catching up” and it has the following chart:
The size of the difference between Alberta and the other Canadian provinces surprises me, but it cites the relevant StatsCan Table so I should be able to reproduce this. Sounds like a nice challenge for my nascent R skills.
I’m a complete beginner with R, so none of the following should be interpreted as best practice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
